■ lucas.b.jennings@gmail.com

(870)-530-1124

in linkedin.com/in

/lucasjennings/

O lbjennings

Education

Springboard
Data Science 2018

University of Arkansas M.S. Mathematics 2011

Emphasis on Topology, Graph Theory, and Networks

Arkansas State University B.S. Mathematics 2005

Skills

Data Science

Machine Learning

Supervised Learning

Unsupervised Learning

Predictive Algorithms

Data Analysis

Financial Analysis

Statistical Analysis

Clustering

Natural Language Processing

Network Analysis

Web Scraping

Data Cleaning

-

Data Wrangling

Data Visualization

Support Vector Machines

Random Forests

Principle Component Anaylsis

GitHub @lbjennings

Docker

Juypter Notebooks

Bokeh

Matplotlib

. Spark

Pyspark

SQL

Awards

Bronze Star Medal

LUCAS JENNINGS

DATA SCIENTIST

Summary

7 + years using data center approach. Turned around a business territory, changed a battlefield campaign, and managed financial portfolios. I've implemented and presented data projects to clients, and senior stake holders. I enjoy programming and diving deep into the story that data tells. Experienced using machine learning, predictive algorithms, and data visualizations.

Employment

United States Army

Chief Intelligence Officer

2016 to Current

Chief officer responsible for collecting, analyzing and distributing intelligence reports. Established cross-functional teams to build data centric projects.

Union Pacific RailRoad

Manager of Operations

2013 to 2016

Turned the business operations around. Led the region from the last to the top performing region. Utilized data driven analysis to target business improvements.

Morgan Stanley

Financial Advisor

2005 to 2008

Built robust portfolio investment strategies and financial reports for individual clients. Routinely conducted statistical analysis and predictive algorithms on financial portfolios and markets.

Projects

Grocery Shopping Habit Analysis

2018

https://github.com/lbjennings/Springboard/Capstone_Project_1

A project to understand and predict customer purchasing habits using machine learning. Algorithms include Support Vector Machine, Random Forest, and Single Vector Decomposition.

Improving the Canadian Interchange System

2016

Project Manager to improve the interchange process between Canada and the United States. Project included time series analysis, network effects, capacity constraints, and statistical applications.

Train Velocity 2015

Project Manager to improve train velocity over the Wisconsin territory. Project included data collection improvement, time series analysis, and critical path analysis.

Counter IED Initiative

A data driven project reducing the IED (improvised explosive device) threat in combat zones. Project utilized machine learning, network analysis, graph theory, and predictive algorithms.

Mini Projects 2018

https://github.com/lbjennings/Springboard/Mini-Projects

Projects include SQL, Clustering, Network Analysis, Linear and Logistic Regression, Naive Bayes, Spark, and Statistically Analysis.